Vivien Kellems Papers 1992.0033
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
- Series III: Activism Papers, undated, 1879-1975
  - (Box 40)
    - Correspondence, 1971
    - Speeches, 1971
    - Newspapers, 1971
    - Single tax battle, 1969-1970
    - Research for book, undated
    - Chapter 1, undated
    - Chapter 2, undated
    - Acknowledgements, Dedication and Index, undated
    - shelton on Thesis, 1970-1974
    - Clippings: Government today, undated, 1968
    - Notes: Separation of pwers, undated
    - Notes: Connecticut reapportionment, undated
    - Boondoggle, undated
    - "Cows and monkeys,", undated
    - Draft of dissertation, 1974
    - Book manuscript, Chapters 4-6, undated
  - (Box 42)
    - Manuscript, pap. 76-112, undated
    - Preface, Introduction and Epilogue, undated
    - Discontents, undated
    - Book Manuscript, undated
    - Book: Steve Ebbin, undated
    - Manuscript, pp. 1-62, undated
    - Manuscript, pp. 1-68, undated
    - "Cows, monkeys and locusts" drafts, undated
    - Liberty Bell research, undated
    - Quakers research, undated
    - Manuscript copies, undated
    - Research for book, undated
    - Bell research, undated
    - Correspondence: David R. Shelton, 1971-1972
    - Single Taxpayer bill, 1969-1972
    - Vivien Kellems v. Commissioner, Internal Revenue Service, 1970
    - Correspondence: David R. Shelton (6 folders), 1969-1974
    - Briefs and Petitions, 1968-1973
    - USA v. James A. Owen, 1972
    - Vivien Kellems v. Commissioner, Internal Revenue Service, 1973-1974
    - Corresopndence: State income tax, 1973
    - Income Tax booklets and information, undated
    - Income tax information (not necessary) and clippings, undated
  - (Box 43)
    - Tax research, undated
    - Court decisions, Shleton's briefs, 1958-1973
    - Correspondence: David R. Shelton, 1969
    - Lawsuit: U.S. Tax Court, 1969-1974
    - Connecticut: Witholding tax, 1948
    - Tax research, undated
    - Research, 1968
    - Publishers, 1968
    - Edinburgh, Scotland bills, 1967-1969
    - Bills, 1968
    - Correspondence: Edinburgh (Hanham), 1968
    - Correspondence: Edinburgh (Templeton), 1967-1970
    - Correspondence: Edinburgh (Timms), 1967-1968
    - University of Edinburgh, 1967-1971
    - Book (Carbons), undated
    - Paul Couts, Ltd., 1968
    - Correspondence: Edinburgh (Books), 1967-1968
    - Zoning, undated, 1957-1969
    - Book, undated, 1974
    - Chapter 2: John Hanson and land, undated
    - Spare and original, undated
    - Chpater 5: Witholding tax, undated
    - Chapter 1, undated
    - Chpater 2, undated
    - Chapter 3, undated
    - Lawsuit: New York District Court, 1968
    - Lawsuit: New Haven transcript and photographs, undated
    - Foreword, undated
    - Clippings, undated
    - Washington, D.C.: hearings and reports, undated, 1969
    - Tax strike, undated
    - Equal Rights Amendment
  - (Box 44)
    - Court decisions, 1945-1971
    - 4th Amendment, undated
    - Research, undated
    - Lawsuit: New Haven, 1970
    - Book materials, undated
    - Property sale, 1968
    - Bills and Receipts, 1967-1968
    - Income tax (2 folders), 1970
    - Money (forms and policies), undated
    - Correspondence, 1968
    - Tax, 1971
    - Radio and television, 1971
    - Columnists, 1971
    - Publications, 1972
    - Clippings, undated
    - Tax Strike, undated, 1972
    - Tax rebellion, undated, 1972
    - Tax on marrieds, 1971-1972
    - Clippings, 1972
    - Radio and Television, 1972
    - Organic Consumer reports, 1972
    - Speeches, 1972
    - Pequot Press, 1972
    - Tax notes, undated, 1966-1967
    - Newspapers, 1972
    - Co$t ( Committee of Single Taxpayers, Inc., 1972
    - Fensterwald and Ohlhausen (Attorneys), 1972
    - Republican Platform, 1972
    - U. S. Senate, 1972
    - U. S. House of Representatives, 1972
    - IRS: Johnnie Walters, 1972
    - New York, 1972
    - North Carolina, 1972
    - Massachusetts, 1972
  - (Box 45)
    - Michigan, 1972
    - Minnesota, 1972
    - Missouri, 1972
    - Montana, 1972
    - Nevada, 1972
    - New Hampshire, 1972
    - New Jersey, 1972
    - New Mexico, 1972
    - New York City, 1972
    - Foreign, 1972
    - Alabama, 1972
    - Alaska, 1972
    - Arizona, 1972
    - Arkansas, 1972
    - California (4 folders), 1972
    - Long Beach, CA, 1972
    - Los Angeles, CA (2 folders), 1972
    - California, Q - R, 1972
    - California, S, 1972
    - California,T - Z, 1972
    - Correspondence: David R. Shelton, 1972
    - Colorado, 1972
    - Connecticut (2 folders), 1972
    - Washignton, D.C., 1972
    - Delaware, 1972
    - Florida (2 folders), 1972
  - (Box 46)
    - Georgia, 1972
    - Hawaii, 1972
    - Idaho, 1972
    - Chicago, IL, 1972
    - Illinois, 1972
    - indiana, 1972
    - Iowa, 1972
    - Kansas, 1972
    - Kentucky, 1972
    - Louisiana, 1972
    - Maine, 1972
    - Maryland, 1972
    - California, 1972
    - Washington, D.C., 1972
    - Florida, 1972
    - Georgia, 1972
    - Hawaii, 1972
    - Illinois, 1972
    - Indiana, 1972
    - Kentucky, 1972
    - Louisiana, 1972
    - Maine, 1972
    - Maryland, 1972
    - Massachusetts, 1972
    - Michigan, 1972
    - Minnesota, 1972
    - Mississippi, 1972
    - Missouri, 1972
    - Nebraska (2 folders), 1972
    - New Hampshire, 1972
    - New Jersey, 1972
    - New York, 1972
    - North Carolina, 1972
    - North Dakota, 1972
    - Ohio, 1972
    - Oklahoma, 1972
    - Oregon, 1972
    - Pennsylvania, 1972
    - Rhode Island, 1972
    - South Carolina, 1972
    - Tennessee, 1972
    - Texas, 1972
    - Utah, 1972
    - Vermont, 1972
    - Virginia, 1972
    - Washington, 1972
    - West Virginia, 1972
    - Wisconsin, 1972
  - (Box 47)
    - Ohio, 1972
    - Oklahoma, 1972
    - Oregon, 1972
    - Pennsylvania, 1972
    - Rhode Island, 1972
    - Tennesee, 1972
    - Texas, 1972
    - Utah, 1972
    - Vermont, 1972
    - Virginia, 1972
    - Washington, 1972
    - Virginia, 1972
    - Wisconsin, 1972
    - Wyoming, 1972
    - California, 197
    - Clippings, 1973
    - Newspapers, 1973
    - Speeches, 1973
    - Television and Radio, 1973
    - Tax rebellion, 1973
    - Correspondence: Wilbur Mills, 1973
    - Co$t, 1973
    - IRS: Johnnie Walters, 1973
    - Correspondence: U. S. House of Representatives, 1973
    - Correspondence: U. S. Senate, 1973
    - Alabama, 1973
    - Arizona, 1973
    - Arkansas, 1973
    - Tax rebellion, 1974
    - Books, 1973
    - Speeches, 1974
    - Television and radio, 1974
    - Correspondence: Social Security, 1974
    - Newspapers, undated
    - Clippings and notes, undated
    - No address, 1973
    - Alaska, 1973
    - Arizona, 1973
    - Arkansas, 1973
    - Colorado, 1973
    - California, 1973
    - Connecticut, 1973
    - Delaware, 1973
    - Washington, D.C., 1973
    - Florida, 1973
    - Georgia, 1973
    - Illinois, 1973
    - Indiana, 1973
    - Kansas, 1973
    - Louisiana, 1973
    - Maryland, 1973
    - Massachusetts, 1973
    - Michigan, 1973
    - Minnesota, 1973
    - Mississippi, 1973
    - Missouri, 1973
    - Nebraska, 1973
    - New Hampshire, 1973
    - New York, 1973
    - New Jersey, 1973
    - New Mexico, 1973
    - North Carolina, 1973
    - Ohio, 1973
    - Oklahoma, 1973
    - Oregon, 1973
    - Pennsylvania, 1973
    - Rhode Isaland, 1973
    - South Carolina, 1973
    - Tennessee, 1973
    - Texas, 1973
    - Utah, 1973
    - Vermont, 1973
    - Virginia, 1973
    - Washington, 1973
    - Wisconsin, 1973
    - Wyoming, 1973
    - land Use, 1973
    - California, 1974
  - (Box 48)
    - New York, 1973
    - Ohio, 1973
    - Oklahoma, 1973
    - Oregon, 1973
    - Pennsylvania, 1973
    - Rhode Island, 1973
    - South Dakota, 1973
    - Tennessee, 1973
    - Texas, 1973
    - Utah, 1973
    - Vermont, 1973
    - Virginia, 1973
    - Washington, 1973
    - Wisconsin, 1973
    - Wyoming, 1973
    - Maine, 1973
    - Maryland, 1973
    - Massahusetts, 1973
    - Michigan, 1973
    - Minnesota, 1973
    - Mississippi, 1973
    - Missouri, 1973
    - New Hampshire, 1973
    - New Jersey, 1973
    - New Mexico, 1973
    - Delaware, 1973
    - Florida, 1973
    - Georgia, 1973
    - Hawaii, 1973
    - Idaho, 1973
    - Illinois, 1973
    - Indiana, 1973
    - Iowa, 1973
    - Kansas, 1973
    - Kentucky, 1973
    - Louisiana, 1973
    - Coloradao, 1973
    - Connecticut, 1973
    - Precision Timer Co., Inc., 1973
    - Connecticut tax issues, 1973
    - Sterling Opera House Foundation, Inc., 1973
    - East Haddam, CT, 1973
    - Education, 1972
    - Greenwich, CT, 1973
    - Hartford, CT, 1973
    - Homer D. Babbidge, Jr., 1973
    - Emanuel R. Cappas, 1973
    - Magazines, 1974
    - Foreign, 1974
    - David R. Shleton, 1974
    - School issues, 1974
    - Contributions: no name, no address, 1974
    - Arizona, 1974
    - California, 1974
    - Colorado, 1974
    - Connecticut, 1974
    - Washington, D.C., 1974
    - Illinois, 1974
    - Indiana, 1974
    - Massachusetts, 1974
    - Michigan, 1974
    - Minnesota, 1974
    - Mississippi, 1974
    - Missouri, 1974
    - Nebraska, 1974
    - New Jersey, 1974
    - New York, 1974
    - North Carolina, 1974
    - North Dakota, 1974
    - Ohio, 1974
    - Oklahoma, 1974
    - Pennsylvania, 1974
    - South Carolina, 1974
    - Tennessee, 1974
    - Texas, 1974
    - Virginia, 1974
    - Washington, 1974
    - West Virginia, 1974
    - Wisconsin, 1974
    - Wall Street Journal ad, 1974
    - No address, 1974
    - Alabama, 1974
    - Arkansas, 1974
    - California, 1974
    - Colorado, 1974
    - Connecticut, 1974
    - Washington, D.C., 1974
    - Florida, 1974
    - Georgia, 1974
    - Illinois, 1974
    - Indiana, 1974
    - Kansas, 1974
    - Kentucky, 1974
    - Louisiana, 1974
    - Michigan, 1974
    - Minnesota, 1974
    - Missouri, 1974
    - Nevada, 1974
    - New Jersey, 1974
    - New York, 1974
    - North Carolina, 1974
    - North Dakota, 1974
    - Ohio, 1974
    - Oklahoma, 1974
    - Oregon, 1974
    - Pennsylvania, 1974
    - Rhode Island, 1974
    - South Carolina, 1974
    - South Dakota, 1974
    - Texas, 1974
    - Virginia, 1974
    - Washington, 1974
    - Wisconsin, 1974
    - Wyoming, 1974
    - Vivien Kellems v. Commissioner of Internal Revenue, 1974
    - California State Bar Journal, 1973 December
    - Co$t, 1974
    - Wilbur Mills, 1974
    - House of Representatives, 1974
    - Senate, 1974
  - (Box 55)
    - Publications, brochures, articles and reports, undated, 1948-circa 1970
      - Income Tax
      - Equal Rights Amendment
      - Port Authority
      - Politics
      - Women
  - Unsorted clippings, undated (Box 56)
  - Unsorted clippings, 1965-1970 (Box 57)
  - Clippings, 1948-1970 (Box 58)
    - Taxes
    - Oveta Cup
    - Foreign policy
    - Speeches
    - Fashion Academy award
    - Senate campaign
    - Politics
    - Minute Women
    - Woman of the Year
  - Clippings: Taxes (sorted by state), 1971, 1973 (Box 59)
  - Clippings, 1945-1958 (Box 60)
    - Taxes
    - Taxes
    - Minute Women
    - Vivien Kellems
    - Speeches
    - Zoning
    - Campaigns: Senate and Gubernatorial
    - Television program
    - Toil, Taxes and Trouble
  - Clippings, 1947-1956 (Box 61)
    - Politics
    - Foreign policy
    - Speeches
    - Louisa F. Kellems
    - Communism
    - CIO case
    - Taxes
    - Marshall Housewives
    - Liberty Belles
    - Polygamy
  - Clippings, 1926-1956 (Box 62)
    - Taxes
    - Speeches
    - Equal Rights
    - Politics
    - Voting machines
    - Marshall Housewives
    - Women's Homework
    - Eddie Richenbacker
    - Vivien Kellems
    - Polygamy
    - Industrial grip application
    - Censorship
    - Brooklyn Eagle
  - Clippings, 1941-1950 (Box 63)
    - Speeches
    - Curfew
    - Edgar E. Kellems
    - Zoning
    - Politics
    - Foreign policy
    - Taxes
    - Equal rights
    - Fashion Academy award
- Series IV: Real Estate Papers, undated, 1872-1976
  - (Box 28)
    - Payroll Tax returns, 1950
    - Travel, 1940s
    - Gas, 1940s
    - Receipts, 1967-1970
    - Appliances, 1970
    - Property Maintenance, undated, 1966-1970
    - Receipts, 1969-1970
    - Legal and financial records, undated, 1920-1954
    - Property Maintenance, 1968-1970
    - Lumber receipts, 1970
    - Utilities, 1968-1970
    - Canton Clothes Dryer, 1939
    - Tax Reassessment of 59 East 64th Street, 1944-1949
    - 131 East 64th Street (NYC) correspondence, 1949-1955
    - 131 East 64th Street (NYC) correspondence with Arthur J. Peck, 1949-1955
    - White Sails Inn, Mystic, CT, receipts, 1964-1965
    - 59 East 64th Street (NYC): Legal, financial and correspondence, 1943-1955
    - 59 East 64th Street (NYC), Swedish Consulate claim, 1946-1947
    - 59 East 64th Street (NYC), Swedish Consulate claim, 1947-1950
    - John B. Benson Isnurance, undated, 1953
    - 131 East 64th Street (NYC) insurance, undated, 1953
    - Real Estate Worman's Compensation insurance, 1949-1953
    - Voluntown, CT farmhouse insurance, 1950-1952
    - Mason's Island, Mystic, Connecticut home insurance, 1950-1953
    - 59 East 64th Street (NYC), 1944-1947
    - Voluntown, CT sale, 1954
    - Correspondence--Farm, 1958
    - Correspondence, 1958
    - Farm--paid bills, 1958
    - Trauntner House, East Haddam, CT, 1965
    - White Sails Inn, 1954-1958
    - 131 East 64th Street (NYC), Legal files, undated, 1872-1950
    - 1 West 67th Street, Inc. v. Vivien Kellems, 1942-1943
    - 59 East 64th Street (NYC), Legal files, 1938-1950
    - Deed, Westport, CT, 1940-1943
    - Newberry Road, East Haddam property, 1976
    - White Sails Inn, Stonington, CT, 1964-1966
    - Wilton Road, Westport, CT, 1937-1950
    - Roofing for Westport home, 1939
    - Westport property and legal records, 1935-1939
    - Furniture imported from Europe, undated, 1938-1956
    - John B. Bension Insurance, 1945
- Series V: Business Papers, undated, 1905-1963
  - (Box 24)
    - Kellems Co., undated
    - Universal Cable Grip Co. acquisition, undated, 1905-1935
    - Kellems Co. factory inquiry, 1936
    - List of NEDA members, Cable grips, undated, 1930s
    - Martin and Son correspondence, 1927-1929
    - Kellems v. Martin
      - Correspondence, 1928-1932
      - Legal, 1928-1932
    - Capen v. Kellems Products, Inc., 1935-1936
    - Fansteel Metalurgical Corporation v. Kellems
      - Correspondence, 1938-1939
      - Legal, 1937-1939
    - Steelman v. Kellems dispute, undated, 1942-1943
    - Vivien Kellems and David Kellems ( Kellems Co.) v. United States of America, undated, 1949-1951
    - Weekley worksheets/checks ( A. T. Coley), 1928
    - Business correspondence
      - 1928
      - 1929
      - 1931
      - 1933
      - 1934
      - 1935
      - 1936
      - 1937
    - Correspondence while away from office, 1944-1947
    - Business correspondence: Sam Longman, 1934
    - Sales of finger grips: George L. Mater, 1935
    - Finger grips: W. C. Westcott
    - Edgar E. Kellems, 1940-1941
    - PMG Metal Trust Limited: Legal, 1929-1948
    - Claude L. Matthews, undated
    - Harry S. Bodin (Attorney for C. L. Matthews), 1941-1942
    - Phelps Dodge Copper Products Corporation, 1936-1942
    - PMG Metal Trust Limited correspondence, undated, 1933-1949
    - Clarkson, Hyde and Company, 1941
    - P.M.G.: V. De Berker, 1931
    - P.M.G.: W. B. Goudielock, 1932-1935
    - P.M.G.: G. F. Harmer, 1931-1935
    - P.M.G.: W. Machin, undated, 1933-1934
    - P.M.G.: A. J. Peck (attorney), 1933-1949
    - Swiss Metalworks Selve and Co., 1930
      - Legal, 1930
      - 1933
      - 1934
      - 1935
      - 1936
      - 1937
      - 1938
      - 1939
  - (Box 25)
    - Joseph Di Palma, 1949
    - 1911-15 Park Avenue, 1936
    - Carter Building, 1941-1946
    - Kellems Co. (WWII) War production, 1945
    - 15-17 William Street, Stonington, Connecticut, 1950
    - Roebling's Sons Company, undated, 1934-1935
    - Balance sheets, 1939
    - Liese Lotte Merzbach Linn, 1945-1946
    - Minutes, 1928-1934
    - Clippings (products, Vivien Kellems), undated, 1934-1935
    - Kellems Cable Grips to Kellems Products, Inc., 1928
    - Kellems Products, Inc. to Kellems Co., 1938-1941
    - Richard Marogg, 1944
    - N. Slater Company, 1939
    - Corn Exchange Trust Company, 1937
    - Ejner Schjoth, 1939
    - International Standard Electric Corporation, 1938
    - Page Patent, undated, 1927-1938
    - Wonham Trading Corporation, Inc., 1928-1929
    - A. E. Samuels and Company v. Repton, undated, 1933-1934
    - Kellems Company Business Correspondence
      - 1928
      - 1930
      - 1932
      - 1933
      - 1934
      - 1935
      - 1937
      - 1938
      - 1939
      - 1941-1942
    - Orders and releases, 1933-1934
    - Edith Glanville, 1936
    - Jonathon Cape, 1936-1937
    - Abercrombie and Rivers, 1934-1935
    - American Steel and Wire Co., 1934
    - Binney and Smith Co., 1932
    - Ray Blain, 1936
    - Briesen and Schrenk, 1930-1932
    - British Ropes Limited, 1937
    - Professor Bowright, 1936
    - Capital Electric Supply Co., 1937
    - Ralph Cleaver, 1936
    - Corn Exchange Bank and Trust Co., 1934-1936
    - E. I. Du Pont de Nemours and Company, 1932
    - Fiwale Equipment Manufacturing Company, 1935-1936
    - Cia Cubana de Electricidad
      - Antonio A. Herschmann, 1950-1951
      - Edward A. Holden, 1950-1951
      - Craig Sutton, 1950
      - Thornton Victory, 1950
    - Electrical Light and Power, 1937
    - Electrical publications, 1937
    - Electrical records, 1930
    - Electrical Trade Publishing Company, 1928-1930
    - Electrical West, 1928-1930
    - Electrical World, 1937
    - Fansteel Metallurgical Corporation, 1937
    - Industrical Engineering, 1930
    - Inland Revenue, 1934
    - Publicity correspondence
      - Electrical World, 1928
      - Hotel New Yorker, 1932
      - Journal of American Engineers, 1928
      - A. M. Maylett, 1937
      - McGraw-Hill Publishing Company, 1937
      - Mutual Telephone Company, 1928
      - Nation's Business, 1937
    - Saunders Norvell, 1934
    - Percy Warren Green (Attorney), 1932
    - Public Utility purchasing, 1930
    - Railway Signaling, 1930
    - John A. Roebling's Sons Company, 1934
    - Sherwin Williams Company, 1932
    - Telephone Engineer, 1928
    - Revere Copper and Brass, 1934-1936
    - Telephnoy Publishing Corp., 1928-1930
    - Lawrence Turner, 1933-1939
    - Westinghouse Electric Supply Company, 1936-1941
    - J. R. Williston and Company, 1936
    - P. M. G. Limited Audit file, 1940-1943
    - Kellems Co. air compressor hose, 1933-1934
    - Carolina Power and Light Co. air compressor hose, 1934
    - Consolidated Gas Co. air compressor hose, 1934
    - Syracuse Lighting Co. air compressor hose, 1934
    - distributed Kellems grip sample correspondence, 1933
    - Catepillar Tractor Co. Kellems self loading trailer, 1928
    - Rochester Gas and Electric Corporation Kellems self loading trailer, 1928
    - Edgar E. Kellems rubber plug, 1938-1939
    - Edgar E. Kellems wire rope, 1938-1939
    - Edgar E. Kellems connector, 1939-1941
    - Cia Venezolana de Electricidad, 1933
    - Electric Bond and Share Company, 1930-1931
    - Electric Bond and Share Company-- George L. Mitchell, 1933-1934
    - Phoenix Utility Company
      - Correspondence, 1931
      - Orders, 1931
      - Correspondence, 1932-1933
      - Orders, 1932-1933
    - Ejner Schjoth correspondence
      - 1935
      - 1936
      - 1937
      - 1938
      - 1939-1940
    - Correspondence about Ejner Schjoth
      - 1938
      - 1935-1938
      - undated, 1935-1938
    - John B. Benson Insurance
      - 1951
      - undated
      - Correspondence, 1950
      - Claim: Samuel B. Erskine, 1950
      - Claim: Raymond Fratus, 1950
      - 1951
      - 1952
      - 1953
  - (Box 26)
    - Business correspondence, 1934
    - Business correspondence, 1936
    - Goodbody and Company, 1939
    - Electrical World ads, 1942
    - P. M. G.: C. L. Matthews, Missouri, 1943
    - Ads and Internal Revenue Service, 1943
    - Kellems war production (2 folders), 1942
    - Kellems Co. zoning battle, 1945-1946
    - P. M. G. Limited, 1940-1945
    - P. M. G. Limited, 1946-1947
    - Kellems Products, Inc., 1945-1947
    - Fansteel Corporation, 1947
    - Clark Getts, Inc., 1947-1949
    - Trademarks, 1948
    - Zoning invitations, 1948
    - Ejner Schjoth, 1948-1949
    - Kellems move from Westport to Stonington, 1949
    - National Association of Manufacturers, 1949
    - Klein and Hart Patents, 1954
    - Hackeling, Oberkirch, Corbin and Co., 1954
    - Kellems Company television, 1956
    - Fernando Cortez Avila, 1957
    - Business trip to Mexico>, 1957
    - David C. Kellems v. Ray Williams, 1958
    - William E. Goudielock, 1958
    - Kellems Company acquisition correspondence, 1962
    - Kellems grips for the industrial market (product guide), undated
    - Payroll taxes for employer returns, 1963